(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
重大告知あり！！
アニソン Night Fever!! 角巻わため生誕祭 2025
Major announcement included!!
Anison Night Fever!! Watame Tsunomaki Birthday Celebration 2025
only my railgun
放て！
Fire!
心に刻んだ夢を
The dreams engraved in my heart
未来さえ置き去りにして
Leaving even the future behind
限界など知らない
Knowing no limits
意味無い
There's no point
この能力（ちから）が
This power...
光散らす
...scatters light
その先に遥かな想いを
With far-off feelings ahead
歩いてきたこの道を振り返ることしか
If the only thing I can do is look back on the path I've walked...
出来ないなら今ここで全てを壊せる
then I'll break everything right here and now.
暗闇に堕ちる街並み 人はどこまで立ち向かえるの？
Fallen cityscapes in the darkness; just how far can people stand against it?
加速するその痛みから誰かをきっと守れるよ
I'm sure I can protect someone from this accelerating pain.
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search my Only my railgun can shoot it.
今すぐ身体中を光の速さで駆け巡った確かな予感
Right now, a definite premonition raced through my body at the speed of light.
掴め！望むものなら残さず輝ける自分らしさで
Seize it! If it's what you desire, you can shine by being yourself without leaving anything behind.
信じてるよあの日の誓いをこの瞳に光る涙
I believe in that day's vow, and the tears shining in these eyes...
それさえも強さになるから
even they will become my strength.
立ち止まると少しだけ感じる切なさに
In the faint sadness I feel when I come to a halt...
戸惑うことないなんて嘘はつかないよ
I won't lie and say I'm never bewildered.
宙に舞うコインが描く放物線が決める運命
The parabola drawn by a coin dancing in the air determines destiny.
打ち出した答えが今日も私の胸を駆け巡る
The answer I struck out races through my heart again today.
Sparkling! The shiny lights awake true desire. Only my railgun can shoot it.
必ず貫いてく途惑うことなく傷ついても走り続ける
I'll always pierce through, without hesitation, continuing to run even if I get hurt.
狙え！凛と煌めく視線は狂いなく闇を切り裂く
Aim! My dignified, sparkling gaze will slice through the darkness without error.
迷いなんて吹き飛ばせばいいこの心が叫ぶ限り
I should just blow away any hesitation as long as my heart screams out.
誰ひとり邪魔などさせない
I won't let anyone get in my way.
儚く舞う無数の願いはこの両手に積もってゆく
The countlessly dancing, fleeting wishes pile up in both my hands.
切り裂く闇に見えてくるのは重く深く切ない記憶
What I see through the cut-open darkness are heavy, deep, and painful memories.
色褪せてゆく現実に揺れる絶望には負けたくない
I don't want to lose to the despair swaying in the fading reality.
私が今私であること胸を張って全て誇れる
That I am who I am right now—I can take pride in all of it.
Looking! The blitz loop this planet to search my Only my railgun can shoot it.
今すぐ身体中を光の速さで駆け巡った確かな予感
Right now, a definite premonition raced through my body at the speed of light.
放て！心に刻んだ夢を未来さえ置き去りにして
Release it! Leave the future itself behind with the dream carved into your heart.
限界など知らない意味ないこの能力(ちから)が光散らす
Boundaries are unknown and meaningless; this power scatters light.
その先に遥かな想いを
With far-off feelings ahead
ギターと孤独と蒼い惑星
Guitars, Loneliness and Blue Planet
突然降る夕立 ああ傘もないや嫌
A sudden evening shower, ah, I don't even have an umbrella, how annoying.
空のご機嫌なんかしらない
I don't care about the sky's mood.
季節の変わり目の服は何着りゃいいんだろ
What should I wear during the change of seasons?
春と秋 どこいっちゃったんだよ
Spring and autumn, where did they go?
息もできない情報の圧力
The pressure of information that leaves me unable to breathe.
めまいの螺旋 私はどこにいる
A spiral of dizziness, where am I?
こんなに こんなに 息の音がするのに
Despite my breath sounding like this, so much...
変だね 世界の音がしない
It's strange, I can't hear the sounds of the world.
足りない　足りない
Not enough, not enough
誰にも気づかれない
Not noticed by anyone
殴り書きみたいな音
Sounds like scribbling
出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed in a state where I couldn't get it out
ありのままなんて
Things as they are...
誰に見せるんだ
Who am I going to show?
馬鹿な私は歌うだけ
Stupid me, I just sing
ぶちまけちゃおうか　星に
Shall I spill it all out to the stars?
エリクサーに張り替える作業も　なんとなくなんだ
Even the task of restringing with Elixirs is just half-hearted
欠けた爪を少し触る
I touch my chipped nail slightly
半径300mmの体で必死に鳴いてる
Crying out desperately with a body of 300mm radius
音楽に酔っちゃえば　ココが地球だな
If I get drunk on music, then this is Earth
空気を握って　空を殴るよ
Grabbing the air and punching the sky
何も起きない　私は無能さ
Nothing happens, I'm incompetent
だけどさその手で　この鉄を弾いたら
But if I pluck these iron strings with that hand
何かが変わって見えた
Something seemed to change
よう眩しい眩しい　そんなに光るなよ
How dazzling, dazzling, don't shine so much
私のダサい影が　より濃くなってしまうだろう
My lame shadow will only grow darker
なんでこんなに熱くなっちゃってんだ　止まんない
Why have I become so hot? I can't stop
馬鹿な私は歌うだけ
Stupid me, I just sing
うるさいんだって心臓
My heart is so loud
蒼い惑星　独りぼっち
Blue planet, all alone
いっぱいの音を聴いてきた
I've heard so many sounds
回り続けて幾億年
Continuing to spin for billions of years
一瞬でもいいから　ああ
Even just for a moment, ah...
聴いて　聴けよ
Listen, listen!
わたし　わたし　わたしはここにいる
I, I, I am right here
殴り書きみたいな音　出せない状態で叫んだよ
I screamed in a state where I couldn't get out these scribbled-like sounds
何かになりたい　なりたい　何者かでいい
I want to be something, I want to be something, anyone will do
馬鹿な私は歌うだけ
Stupid me, I just sing
ぶちまけちゃおうか　星に
Shall I spill it all out to the stars?
歌聞いてくれてありがとう！
Thanks for listening to my song!
聞いてくれるこの環境、とっても嬉しく思います！
I'm so happy to have this environment where people listen to me!
いやー、『ギターと孤独と蒼い惑星』もね、もうかなり難しくて、
Man, "Guitars and Solitude and the Blue Planet" was really difficult,
練習頑張ったんで、どうだったかな？
and I worked hard on practicing it, so I wonder how it was?
よかった？嬉しいよー！
Was it good? I'm so happy!
あ、ホロライブ4期生、角巻わためです！
Ah, I'm Tsunomaki Watame of Hololive Gen 4!
これ見よがしに弾いております！
I'm playing this ostentatiously!
今日でなんと、9歳になりました！
And today, I turned 9 years old!
お祝いっぱいありがとう！
Thank you for all the celebrations!
ありがとうございます、ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much, thank you so much.
いや、この日のために、もうたくさん、たくさん頑張って準備もしてきたので。
Man, I've worked so hard and prepared so much for this day.
ぜひ最後まで、見て楽しんでほしいなと思います！
So I hope you'll watch and enjoy until the very end!
よろしくべいべー！
Rock on, baby!
ということでね、これはあの、片付けますね。
And with that, I'm going to put this away.
もう使わないのでね。
I won't be using it anymore.
はい、ちょっと待っててね。よいしょ、よいしょ。
Okay, wait a bit. Heave-ho, heave-ho.
よいしょっと。このギターが、ギターが...
There we go. This guitar, the guitar...
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
肩凝りになっちまう。
I'm going to get stiff shoulders.
やー待っててくれてありがとう。ございます。
Thanks for waiting. Thank you.
今日のハッシュタグは！なんと！前代未聞！
Today's hashtag is! Unbelievable! Unprecedented!
こちら！ #角巻わため生誕祭2025 なので！
This! #TsunomakiWatameBirthday2025!
こちらのハッシュタグを付けて、もうたくさん、たくさんポストしていただけると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you could use this hashtag and post a ton!
今日はアニソンナイトフィーバー、楽しんでいけますかー！
Can we enjoy Anime Song Night Fever today?!
いけますかー！
Can we?!
わためは、いけます！
Watame is ready!
では、アニソンナイトフィーバー、行くぞー！
Then, Anime Song Night Fever, let's go!
ん？
Hm?
何だこれは？
What is this?
こんなのステージに置いてあったら いけないでしょ
You can't have things like this just lying on the stage.
つぎに...
Next...
なにこれ？
What is this?
あ、何なの？
Oh, what is it?
誰 これ置いたの？
Who put this here?
あ...
Oh...
なんじゃこりゃ！
What the heck is this?!
渇いた叫び
Kawaita Sakebi
作詞・作曲：小松未歩
Lyrics/Composition: Miho Komatsu
このままもう少し歩こう 肩を抱き
Let's walk just a bit further like this, arm in arm
消えゆく夢を数え枯れてく仲間を見た
I watched friends wither as they counted their fading dreams
通い慣れた道に迷い込むこのごろ
Lately, I've been getting lost on familiar paths
闇がもう一人の自分をつくる
The darkness creates another version of myself
渇いた叫びがくじけそうな
A parched shout pierces through
胸を突き刺す
my disheartened chest
君を誘って世界を見たいな
I want to invite you along to see the world
だれにも出せない答えが
The answer no one else can give
僕の中にある
lies within me
駆け引きがカギ
The bargaining is the key
とどけ fly at higher game
Reach out, fly at higher game
いくつの悲しみを一緒に越えただろう？
I wonder how many sorrows we've overcome together?
気が済むまで求めたあの日の僕達がいた
We were there that day, searching until satisfied
時代が巡るなら またどこかで会えるね
If the times come around, we'll meet again somewhere
その時が来るまで諦めない
I won't give up until that time comes
冷めてく想いは どうしても否めないけど
Though I can't deny my feelings are cooling down
恋に落ちて変わってくのもいいね
It's also nice to fall in love and change
焦らず騒がずあるがままでと願うから
I wish to stay as I am, without rushing or fussing
心に花を
Let a flower in our hearts
咲かそう just take my heart
bloom; just take my heart
渇いた叫びがくじけそうな
A parched shout pierces through
胸を突き刺す
my disheartened chest
君を誘って世界を見たいな
I want to invite you along to see the world
だれにも出せない答えが
The answer no one else can give
夢の中にある
lies within my dreams
僕を信じて
Believe in me
咲かそう just take my heart
Let it bloom; just take my heart
人生は続いてく
Life goes on
カサブタ
作詞・作曲：千綿偉功
Kasabuta
Lyrics/Composition: Chiwata Hidenori
明日へ続く坂道の途中で
Halfway up the slope that leads to tomorrow
すれ違う大人たちはつぶやくのさ
The adults passing by whisper to themselves
愛とか夢とか理想も解るけど
I understand things like love, dreams, and ideals
目の前の現実はそんなに甘くないって
But they say reality isn't that sweet
つまずきながらも
Though we stumble
転がりながらも
Though we roll along
カサブタだらけの情熱を忘れたくない
I don't want to forget this passion covered in scabs
大人になれない僕らの 強がりをひとつ聞いてくれ
Listen to one show of strength from us who can't grow up
逃げも隠れもしないから
We won't run or hide
笑いたい奴だけ笑え
So those who want to laugh can laugh
せめて頼りない僕らの 自由の芽を摘み取らないで
At least don't pluck the sprouts of freedom from us who are unreliable
水をあげるその役目を 果たせばいいんだろう？
It's fine as long as we fulfill the role of watering them, right?
何度も繰り返した失敗とか
The failures we've repeated over and over
大きく食い違った考えとか
The ideas that were so far apart
僕らの基準はとても不確かで
Our standards are so uncertain
昨日より何となく歩幅が広くなった
Somehow my stride feels wider than yesterday
背伸びをしながら
While stretching ourselves thin
打ちのめされながら
While being beaten down
カサブタをちょっとはがすけど 答えは出ない
I peel off a scab a bit, but there's no answer
大人になりたい僕らの わがままをひとつ聞いてくれ
Listen to one selfish wish from us who want to grow up
寝ても覚めても縛られる
Bound whether asleep or awake
時間を少しだけ止めて
Just stop time for a little while
せめてふがいない僕らの 自由の実を切り取らないで
At least don't cut off the fruits of freedom from us who are pathetic
赤く熟すその時まで 悩めばいいんだろう
It's fine as long as we worry until they ripen red
大人になれない僕らの 強がりをひとつ聞いてくれ
Listen to one show of strength from us who can't grow up
逃げも隠れもしないから
We won't run or hide
笑いたい奴だけ笑え
So those who want to laugh can laugh
せめて頼りない僕らの 自由の芽を摘み取らないで
At least don't pluck the sprouts of freedom from us who are unreliable
水をあげるその役目を 果たせばいいんだろう
It's fine as long as we fulfill the role of watering them, right?
Catch You Catch Me
作詞・作曲：広瀬香美
Lyrics/Composition: Kohmi Hirose
会いたいな
I want to see you
会えないな
I can't see you
切ないな この気持ち
It's painful, this feeling
言えないな
I can't say it
言いたいな
I want to say it
チャンス 逃してばかり
I keep missing every chance
だって だって だって
Because, because, because
翼広げ二人で
Spreading our wings together
空をマラソン
Marathon through the sky
夢をユニゾンしたい
I want our dreams in unison
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me 待って
See? Catch you, catch you, catch me, catch me... wait
こっちを向いて
Look my way
スキだといって
Tell me you love me
そう Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
That's right, nice to meet you, good to see you, surely
私の想い あなたのハートに 飛んで飛んで飛んで行け
Let my feelings fly, fly, fly into your heart
迷わない
I won't hesitate
たまにね 無くなっちゃう
Sometimes it just runs out
身体のバッテリー
The body's battery
あなたの笑顔で いつも充電満タン
Your smile always gives me a full charge
パワー全開
Power at full blast
パワー爆発しちゃう
My power is about to explode
お願い お願い お願い お願い
Please, please, please, please
まだねお友達かな
Are we still just friends?
笑って見つめて楽しい毎日にしたい
I want to smile and look at you, and make every day fun
ほら Catch You Catch You Catch Me Catch Me ゼッタイ
Look, I'll definitely Catch You Catch Me
運命だって お似合いだって そう
Because it's fate, because we're a perfect match, yes
Nice to Meet You Good to See You きっと
Nice to meet you, good to see you, surely
誰にも負けない あなたに世界で一番
I won't lose to anyone, to you, the most in the world
コ・イ・シ・テ・ル
I'm in love with you
また夢から覚める 濡れた瞼を開ける
Waking from a dream again, opening my wet eyelids
狂おしいほど思い残す 遠い日の無力を呪う
Left with regrets so intense it's maddening, cursing the helplessness of distant days
身を焼かれるような絶望も糧にはなろうか
Will even the despair that feels like it's burning my body become nourishment?
憧れに焦がれるまま燃やし続けている
Continuing to burn while longing for my aspirations
キラキラな星様したあなたのeyes
Your eyes, like twinkling stars
カラカラ渇いて可哀想なlack of 愛？
Parched and pitiful, a lack of love?
全てを孤独から救う眩しい光
A dazzling light that saves everything from loneliness
僕にだけ落ちる shadow はあなたのせい？
Is the shadow falling only on me your fault?
致命的な欠落をくれたね
You gave me a fatal deficiency
身勝手な巨星 狂わされた生
A selfish giant star, a life driven mad
お願い、声を聞かせて、声を聞かせて
Please, let me hear your voice, let me hear your voice
絡まって歪んでしまった僕らに
To us, who have become entangled and distorted
くれたのはあなただけ、あなただけ
The one who gave it was only you, only you
(ああ、あなただけ、あなただけ)
(Ah, only you, only you)
お願い、僕を見ていて、僕を見ていて
Please, keep looking at me, keep looking at me
宿命に刻まれた痛みさえ武器にして
Turning even the pain carved into destiny into a weapon
いつかの後悔すら照らせるように
So that even someday's regrets can be illuminated
あなたがいないと生きていけない
I can't live without you
何もかも捧げてしまっていい
It's fine to sacrifice everything
あなたの愛がまだ足りない
Your love is still not enough
欠けたものは何で埋めたらいい？
What should I fill the missing pieces with?
致命的、致命的、致命的な愛
Fatal, fatal, fatal love
運命的、運命的、運命的な愛
Fateful, fateful, fateful love
必然的、必然的、必然的な哀
Inevitable, inevitable, inevitable sorrow
僕を見ていてね
Keep looking at me
最愛のファタール！
My dearest Fatale!
キラキラな星様したあなたのeyes
Your eyes, like twinkling stars
カラカラ渇いて可哀想なlack of 愛？
Parched and pitiful, a lack of love?
遥か彼方から放たれた美しさに
At the beauty emitted from far, far away
灼かれた眼、捥がれた羽、創造的堕天
Burned eyes, torn wings, a creative fall from grace
あらゆる視界をジャック その輝きはエゴイスティック
Hijacking all fields of vision, that brilliance is egoistic
胸の奥仕舞った感傷さえ引っ張り出して昇華して
Pulling out even the sentimentality hidden deep in my heart and sublimating it
僕という運命を全部抱きしめてゆく
I'll embrace all of the destiny that is me
あなたがいないと生きていけない
I can't live without you
眩しさでこの身を照らして欲しい
I want you to illuminate this body with brilliance
あなたの愛がまだ足りない
Your love is still not enough
夢の中で貰うしかないのに
Even though I can only receive it in a dream
致命的、致命的、致命的な愛
Fatal, fatal, fatal love
運命的、運命前、運命的な愛
Fateful, fateful, fateful love
必然的、必然的、必然的な哀
Inevitable, inevitable, inevitable sorrow
誰のものでもない 最愛のファタール！
Belonging to no one, my dearest Fatale!
何度悔やんだだろう 何度呪っただろう
How many times have I regretted it? How many times have I cursed it?
どれほどの幸福を注いだとしても
No matter how much happiness I pour in
満たされることのない器
A vessel that can never be filled
何度夢見ただろう 何度願っただろう
How many times have I dreamed of it? How many times have I wished for it?
僕の胸で膿み続けている傷を撫でる手を
For a hand to stroke the wound that continues to fester in my chest
僕の胸で震え続けている傷を撫でる手を
With a hand that strokes the wound still trembling in my chest
この舞台で足掻くことをやめない
I won't stop struggling on this stage
ただ一つのアイに近づきたい
I want to get closer to that one and only "Ai"
固く定まったこの宿命
This destiny that has been firmly decided
あの星の光からこぼれた闇
The darkness that spilled from the light of that star
あなたがいないと生きていけない
I can't live without you
何もかも捧げてしまっていい
I'm fine with giving up everything
あなたの愛がまだ足りない
Your love is still not enough
欠けたものは何で埋めたらいい？
What should I use to fill what's missing?
致命的、致命的、致命的な愛
Fatal, fatal, fatal love
運命的、運命的、運命的な愛
Fated, fated, fated love
必然的、必然的、必然的な愛
Inevitable, inevitable, inevitable love
僕を見ていてね
Keep your eyes on me
最愛のファタール！
My beloved fatal!
You're fatal
最愛のファタール
My beloved fatal
まるで御伽の話
Like a fairy tale
終わり迎えた証
The sign that it has ended
長過ぎる旅路から
From the journey that was too long
切り出した一節
A single verse cut out
それはかつてこの地に
It was once in this land
影を落とした悪を
The evil that cast a shadow
討ち取りし勇者との
With the hero who struck it down
短い旅の記憶
Memories of a short journey
物語は終わり
The story ends
勇者は眠りにつく
The hero falls into slumber
穏やかな日常を　この地に残して
Leaving a peaceful daily life in this land
時の流れは無情に　人を忘れさせる
The passage of time heartlessly makes people forget
そこに生きた軌跡も　錆び付いていく
Even the traces of living there begin to rust
それでも君の　言葉も願いも勇気も
Even so, your words, your wishes, and your courage
今も確かに　私の中で生きてる
Are still certainly alive within me
同じ道を選んだ
We chose the same path
それだけだったはずなのに
That was all it was supposed to be, and yet
いつからかどうして
Since when and why
頬を伝う涙の理由を
The reason for the tears streaming down my cheeks
もっと知りたいんだ
I want to know more about it
今更だって　共に歩んだ旅路を辿れば
Even if it's too late, if I retrace the journey we walked together
そこに君はいなくとも　きっと見つけられる
Even if you're not there, I'll surely be able to find it
物語は続く
The story continues
一人の旅へと発つ
Setting off on a journey alone
立ち寄る街で出会う人の
In the people I meet in the towns I stop at
記憶の中に残る君は
You, who remains in their memories
相も変わらずお人好しで
Are as much of a softie as ever
格好つけてばかりだね
And just always trying to look cool, aren't you?
あちらこちらに作ったシンボルは
The symbols you made here and there
勝ち取った平和の証
Are the proof of the peace you won
それすら未来でいつか
So that even in the future someday
私が一人にならないように
I won't be alone
あの旅を思い出せるように
So that I can remember that journey
残された目印
A mark left behind
まるで御伽の話
Like a fairy tale
終わり迎えた証
The sign that it has ended
私を変えた出会い
The encounter that changed me
百分の一の旅路
One-hundredth of a journey
君の勇気をいつか　風がさらって
Even if the wind carries away your courage someday
誰の記憶から消えてしまっても
And it disappears from everyone's memory
私が未来に連れて行くから
I will take it with me into the future
君の手を取った
I took your hand
あの日全て始まった
Everything started that day
くだらなくて思わずふっと
So silly that I can't help but
笑ってしまうような
Suddenly burst out laughing
ありふれた時間が　今も眩しい
That commonplace time is still dazzling even now
知りたいんだ
I want to know
今更だって振り返ると
Even if it's too late, looking back
そこにはいつでも
There you always are
優しく微笑みかける君がいるから
Smiling gently at me
新たな旅の始まりは
The beginning of a new journey is
君が守り抜いたこの地に
In this land that you protected to the end
芽吹いた命と共に
Together with the life that has sprouted
勇者、いい曲だったね〜。
"The Brave," that was a great song, wasn't it?
うん。
Yeah.
VJとかもね、あ、VJっていうのは
Even the VJ... Oh, by VJ
この後ろのMVのことなんだけど。
I mean the MV behind me.
VJとかもね、こだわってみたので、
Since I was really particular about the VJ as well,
ぜひぜひ、いっぱい見てもらいたいな。
I'd really, really love for you all to watch it a lot.
アーカイブとかもね。
In the archives and such.
あ、まだ終わってないけどね！
Oh, it's not over yet, though!
いや、ゲストさんもいっぱい来てくれて嬉しいよ〜！
I'm so happy so many guests came as well!
ありがと〜！
Thank you!
はぁ。
*Sigh*
なんかさ、今までのセトリさ、
You know, the setlist so far,
あの、平成の...
it's been like Heisei era...
...とか、まあ令和のアニソンとかを盛り込んでみたんだけど、知ってる曲はありましたか？
...and some Reiwa-era anime songs. Did you know any of the songs?
お気に入りの曲とかあったかな？
Did you find any favorites?
なんか好きな曲とか、もし見つかったりしたら、
If you found any songs you liked...
教えてほしいなと思います。この曲よかったよ、とか教えてください。
...I'd love to know. Please tell me which ones you enjoyed.
あ、今コメントで教えてくれてもいいんだよ。
Oh, you can tell me in the comments right now too.
うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
でも！これで終わりじゃないんだよね！
But! That's not all!
一曲だけ、まあこの後、
Just one more song after this...
ちょっとゲームの曲とかもなんか混ざってんだけど、
...it's mixed with some game songs, but...
あの、コンセプトがあるセトリになってます。この後。
...the setlist has a concept from here on.
探してみてもらえると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you tried to figure it out.
ゲストさんもね、まだ出ていない人もいるので、楽しみにしててくださーい！
And there are still more guests to come, so please look forward to it!
よーし。
Alright.
では、聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for an unstoppable future
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
Embracing an unyielding wish
ゆずれない願い
作詞：田村直美 作曲：田村直美／石川寛門
Unyielding Wish
Lyrics: Naomi Tamura, Composition: Naomi Tamura / Hiroto Ishikawa
海の色が赤く染まってゆく 無重力状態
The color of the sea turns red, a state of weightlessness
このまま風にさらわれたい
I want to be swept away by the wind just like this
いつも飛べないハードルを 負けない気持ちでクリアしてきたけど
I've always cleared the hurdles I couldn't jump over with a spirit that wouldn't lose, but...
出し切れない実力は 誰のせい？
Whose fault is the power I can't fully bring out?
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for an unstoppable future
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
Embracing an unyielding wish
色褪せない心の地図 光にかざそう
Let's hold up the unfading map in our hearts to the light
どれだけ泣けば朝に出会えるの 孤独な夜
How much more must I cry to meet the morning in this lonely night?
初めて限界を感じた日
The day I first felt my limits
きっと恋に落ちるのは 瞬きみたいな一瞬の情熱だけど
Falling in love is surely an instant's passion, like a blink, but...
愛に続く坂道で 強さ覚えたい
I want to learn strength on the slope that leads to love
止まらない未来を夢見て
Dreaming of an unstoppable future
口を閉ざし瞳を輝かせてきたけれど
I've kept my mouth shut and my eyes shining, but...
もっと大きな優しさが見えた
I saw a much greater kindness
飛べないハードルを 負けない気持ちでクリアしてきたけど
I've cleared the hurdles I couldn't jump over with a spirit that wouldn't lose, but...
スタートラインに立つたびに 怯えていた
Every time I stood at the starting line, I was afraid
止まらない未来を描いて
Picturing an unstoppable future
腕を伸ばし心を開いて
Stretching out my arms and opening my heart
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for an unstoppable future
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
Embracing an unyielding wish
色褪せない心の地図 光にかざそう
Let's hold up the unfading map in our hearts to the light
GONG
作詞：影山ヒロノブ
作曲：影山ヒロノブ / 河野陽吾
GONG
Lyrics: Hironobu Kageyama
Composition: Hironobu Kageyama / Yogo Kono
胸にこみ上げてく
Welling up in my chest
熱く激しいこの想い
This hot and intense feeling
僕らは行く　最後の戦場へ
We are going to the final battlefield
手を取り合い　誓い合って
Holding hands and making a vow
明日の夜明け前に
Before tomorrow's dawn
あの宇宙(そら)へと旅立つのさ
We'll set off for that sky
僕らが地球(ほし)にいたことだけ
Just the fact that we were on this planet
どうか覚えていて欲しいよ
Please remember it
振り向くな
Don't look back
涙を見せるな
Don't show your tears
I GET THE POWER OF LOVE
明日を取り戻すんだ
We'll take back tomorrow
(Woh woh woh)
GONG 鳴らせ！！
Ring the GONG!!
今こそ立ち上がれ
Now is the time to stand up
運命の戦士よ
Oh, warriors of fate
稲妻の剣で敵を蹴散らせ
Scatter the enemy with lightning swords
安らぎを夢見る
Dreaming of peace
鋼の勇者よ
Oh, heroes of steel
守るべき未来と愛を信じて
Believe in the future you must protect and in love
永遠へ！
To eternity!
もしも力尽きて
Even if our strength fails
闘志の刃砕けても
Even if the blade of our fighting spirit shatters
僕らは二度と戻らない
We will never return
ともに銀河の海に散ろう
Let us fall together into the sea of the galaxy
恐れるな
Have no fear
誇りを捨てるな
Don't throw away your pride
I GET THE POWER OF LOVE
さぁ迷わず行くんだ！
Now, go forth without hesitation!
(Woh woh woh)
GONG 鳴らせ！！
Ring the GONG!!
雄々しく舞い踊れ
Dance manfully
運命の戦士よ
Oh, warriors of fate
金色の翼で天に羽ばたけ
Flap your golden wings to the heavens
退くことを知らない
Knowing no retreat
鋼の勇者よ
Oh, heroes of steel
燃えたぎるソウルの命ずるままに
As your burning soul commands
永遠へ！
To eternity!
GONG GONG GONG 鳴らせ！！
Ring the GONG GONG GONG!!
今こそ立ち上がれ
Now is the time to stand up
運命の戦士よ
Oh, warriors of fate
稲妻の剣で敵を蹴散らせ
Scatter the enemy with lightning swords
安らぎを夢見る
Dreaming of peace
鋼の勇者よ
Oh, heroes of steel
守るべき未来と愛を信じて
Believe in the future you must protect and in love
永遠へ！
To eternity!
空色デイズ
Sorairo Days
君は聴こえる？
Can you hear it?
僕のこの声が
This voice of mine
闇に虚しく
In the darkness, in vain
吸い込まれた
It was swallowed up
もしも世界が
If the world
意味を持つのなら
Were to have a meaning
こんな気持ちも
Then even these feelings
無駄ではない
Wouldn't be in vain
憧れに押しつぶされて
Crushed by my yearnings
あきらめてたんだ
I had given up
果てしない空の色も
Even the color of the endless sky
知らないで
Without knowing
走り出した
I've started running
想いが今でも
With feelings that, even now
この胸を確かに
Are surely beating
叩いてるから
Within this chest
今日の僕が
Today's "me" will
その先に続く
Build a tomorrow
僕らなりの
In our own way
明日を築いていく
That continues on ahead
答えはそう
The answer, yes
いつもここにある
Is always right here
過ぎた季節を
I don't have time
嘆く暇はない
To lament the seasons gone by
二度と迷って
So that I won't get lost
しまわぬように
Ever again
数えきれない
The countless
ほんのささやかな
Tiny regrets
そんな後悔
I held them
抱えたまま
Close to me
その背中だけ追いかけて
Chasing only after your back
ここまで来たんだ
I've come this far
探していた
I've found something
僕だけにできること
That only I can do
あの日くれた
The words you gave me
言葉が今でも
That day are still
この胸に確かに
Surely reaching
届いてるから
Into my heart
昨日よりも
More than yesterday
今日僕は僕の
Today I'm realizing
生まれてきた
The reason
理由に気付いていく
That I was born
答えはそう
The answer, yes
いつもここにある
Is always right here
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
だいぶ楽しいねー！
This is so much fun!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
もっとー！
More!
みんなありがとー！
Thank you everyone!
全てがまるで
Everything was as if
当たり前みたいだった
It were only natural
尊い日々は
The precious days
まだ終わらない
Have not ended yet
そしてまた
And then again
走り出した
I've started running
想いが今でも
With feelings that, even now
この胸を確かに
Are surely beating
叩いてるから
Within this chest
今日の僕が
Today's "me" will
その先に続く
Build a tomorrow
僕らなりの
In our own way
明日を築いていく
That continues on ahead
答えはそう
The answer, yes
いつもここにある
Is always right here
みんなー！
Everyone!
ギリワルのロボ、かっこよかったー！
The Giriwaru robot was so cool!
ロボット、乗って飛んじゃったよー！
I rode the robot and flew!
すごい！かっこよかったよねー！
Amazing! It was cool, right?
いや、この3曲はロボットの曲をテーマに
Well, these three songs...
歌って躍らせていただきましたー！
...were performed with a robot theme!
さらにゲストもね、たくさん出演してくれて
And many guests appeared...
本当にありがとー！嬉しい！
...thank you so much! I'm so happy!
はーい！ありがとうございました！感謝です！
Hi! Thank you so much! I'm grateful!
あ、そういえば、ころころ、ころころ、みんな気づいたかな？
Ah, by the way, did everyone notice the rolling?
ころころ最初から実はそうだったんだけど、あの小顔ローラーがんばりまして
I've actually been doing it since the beginning,
but I worked hard with that face roller.
実はわため、小顔になったんですよね、こう見えて
Believe it or not, Watame's face actually got smaller.
もうあれだね、顔デカって言われなくなっちゃうな、みんなめんごめんご
Now I won't be called "big face" anymore.
Sorry about that, everyone!
そんな変わってないって、言わない！言わない！
Don't say it hasn't changed! Don't! Don't!
ちゃんとちっちゃくなったんだ！
It definitely got smaller!
あ、このあとね、メン限3Dライブも10時15分からわためチャンネルでやりますので
Ah, after this, I'll be doing a membership-only
3D live on the Watame Channel from 10:15 PM.
他の衣装のね、この小顔のわためも見てほしいなと思います
So I'd like you to see this small-faced Watame
in other outfits too.
歌って踊りますんで、ぜひ10時15分メンバーシップに入ってお待ちください
I'll be singing and dancing, so please join
the membership and wait for 10:15 PM.
でも！まだライブも終わりではありません！ここで告知があります！
But! The live show isn't over yet!
I have an announcement to make!
角巻わための新曲...「ビリ」、なんと発表いたします！
Tsunomaki Watame's new song... "Biri"!
I'm announcing it now!
このあと10時からMVが投稿されて、で、楽曲配信が24時から始まります！
The MV will be posted at 10 PM, and the
digital release starts at midnight!
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
神田ジョンさん、篠崎あやとさん、DECO*27さんという布陣で作った
It was made by a team consisting of
Kanda John, Ayato Shinozaki, and DECO*27.
わための新しく、あたらしい部分だったりとか、まあちょっとあんまり歌ったことないような感じの曲になっているかなと思っているので
I think it shows a new side of Watame, and it's a type
of song I haven't really sung much before.
ぜひ楽しみにしててください！あ、でも！
So please look forward to it! Oh, but...!
あ、でもこのあと、まだ一曲ぐらいをやる時間があるか...
Oh, but wait, there's still time for about
one more song after this...
はあ、はあ、じゃあ、ビリやろうか！
Yeah, yeah... then shall we do "Biri"?
えー、あと一曲、ビリ、新曲。ぜひみんなに聴いていただきたいなと思うので
Well, one last song. "Biri", the new song.
I'd really like everyone to hear it.
最後まで、あのダンスも可愛いんで、ちょっと一生懸命踊ります。見てください！
Until the end... the dance is cute too, so I'll
do my best. Please watch!
では、最後の曲、聴いてください。ビリ。
Well then, please listen to the final song: "Biri".
三度毎度でグダダダダ
Another flop, every single time
もうハイローガチャでぐちゃぐちゃ
Messy high-low gacha games
同情少年ポジグダダダ
Sympathy seeking, a sloppy position
毎回歌うわなんてこったい感
I sing it every time, feeling like "good grief"
三度やるだけやるしかない
Might as well just do it one more time
もう小さいことで凹んでらんないわ
Can't be getting depressed over the small stuff anymore
全うするまで育つだけさ
Just gotta grow until I see it through
心配いらずのジェットコースター
A worry-free roller coaster
研ぎ上げた五感で
With my senses sharpened
おめかしさぞかしハッピーでいっぱい
Dressed up and surely full of happiness
描き込んだ願いが
The wishes I've sketched in
香り立つ今僕になるんだ
Will become me now, fragrant and blooming
僕しかできないこと
The things only I can do
認めてほしいの
I want you to acknowledge them
「どうせ」とか思ってらんないわ
I can't keep thinking "well, whatever"
妄言ばこん！切り刻んでいこう
Nonsense, pow! Let's slice it all up
まだ一等賞まで放電がありそう
Seems like there's still a spark left for first place
当選しちゃうかは挑戦次第
Whether I win or not depends on the challenge
やるかやらないかだ
It's about whether you do it or not
「はぁめんどっぽい」これでエンドっぽい
"Ugh, what a pain." Seems like this is the end
叩き潰した弱音がちょー痛い
The complaints I crushed are super painful
夢が叶っちゃって甘くなれ
My dreams came true, so get soft
黙れ！判定はノーノーノー グッバイ
Shut up! The verdict is no-no-no, goodbye
三度やるだけやるだけバッド
One more time, just doing it is bad enough
もう涙腺アミダ全泣きが確定
My tear ducts are a lottery, crying is guaranteed
同情求めてはわわわわわ
Seeking sympathy, hawawawa
ねえちゃんと抱きしめて
Hey, hold me tight
顔出した絶望で
With the despair that peeked out
ごまかし乗る歌詞ハッピーが足んない
Lyrics riding on deception, not enough happiness
あたしを愛せない
I can't love myself
比べたら比べるだけ負け犬（ルーザー）
If I compare, I'm just a loser the more I do
ありなし選べちゃうけど
I can choose between "yes" or "no"
弱気になるかも
But I might get cold feet
「どうせ無理」思って仕舞っちゃうわ
I'll end up thinking "it's impossible anyway"
有言だもん！叶わないもん
Because I said it! Because it won't come true
また一等賞指くわえて見てるの
Watching first place again with envy
あたしじゃない誰かだったの
It was someone who isn't me
ノーノー誰か代わってよ
No, no, someone trade places with me
せーので間違いの未来
One, two, a mistaken future
前進もっとハイになって
Moving forward, get even higher
贅沢夢見ていたい
I want to keep dreaming big
声にしたい 息ができない
I want to speak out, but I can't breathe
ローさん黙ってね？
Ro-san, please be quiet, okay?
Wa wa 全部無駄に決まってるじゃん
Wa wa, it's all decided to be a waste, right?
はあ？さあさあ 圧が強すぎる ブレーキ
Huh? Well, well, the pressure is too strong, brake
ブレーキ、アクセル 噛み合わないね 笑えるくらい
Brake, accel, they don't mesh, it's almost laughable
それならこのまま行くしかないか
Then, I guess I have no choice but to go like this
やっぱり分担 それのがいいか
As expected, sharing it, is that better?
大丈夫 無理無理 重ねて
It's okay, impossible impossible, layering it
僕しか会えない子と仲良くしてるの
I'm getting along with the one only I can see
どうせならかまして見ちゃいますか
In that case, shall we try to make an impact?
かまして見ちゃいますか
Shall we try to make an impact?
妄言はぱーん 切り裂いていけ
Delusions are 'bang!' Rip through them
また一丁 しゃにむに加えて見てても
One more time, even if I try to add it recklessly
誰かじゃない僕がいいんだよ
Not someone else, I'm the one who's fine
OK！明日を叶えるんだ
OK! I'll make tomorrow come true
鳴呼 飛ばせ！ 溢れ出せば
Ah, fly! If it overflows
すり倒した美学でぐちゃみたい
Worn down, it's like a mess with aesthetics
夢が叶ったって止まらねー 黙れ！
Even if dreams come true, I won't stop, shut up!
不完全は No No No No No No Goodbye
Incompleteness is no, no, no, no, no, no, goodbye
ビリ ビリ ビリ
Biri biri biri
ビリ ビリ ビリ ビリ
Biri biri biri biri
みんなー！
Everyone!
角巻わため生誕祭2025 アニソンNight Fever!!
Watame Birthday 2025: Anison Night Fever!!
楽しんでいただけましたでしょうかー！
Did you all enjoy it?!
ここからは告知がありますので、
I have some announcements from here,
もう少しお付き合いお願いします！
so please stay with me for a bit longer!
まず、さっきも告知させていただきましたが、
First, as I announced earlier,
この後10時にわためチャンネルにて、
at 10 PM today on the Watame Channel,
角巻わための新曲「ビリ」のMVが公開されます！
my new song 'Biri's MV will be released!
チャンネルはそのままでお願いします！
Please stay tuned to the channel!
そして24時から「ビリ」の楽曲配信も始まりますので、
And starting at midnight, 'Biri' will be available,
ぜひ3rdライブを実現させるためにも、買っていただけると嬉しいです！
so I'd be happy if you'd buy it to help make the 3rd live a reality!
さらに、この後10時から
Furthermore, from 10 PM today,
角巻わため生誕記念2025のグッズが発売開始になります！
Watame Birthday 2025 merch will go on sale!
フルセットはこんな感じなんですが、
This is what the full set looks like,
一つずつ紹介したいと思います！
but I'd like to introduce each item one by one!
まず、ふーみママ描き下ろしのTシャツ！
First, the T-shirt with an illustration by Fuumi-mama!
正面はポケットから出てる風のわためぇとがいます。
On the front, there's Watamate popping out of a pocket.
背面には「あよっ」って感じで挨拶してるわためがいるので、
On the back, there's Watame saying 'Ayo!',
後ろの人から見ても楽しめるTシャツとなっております！
so it's a T-shirt that can be enjoyed even from behind!
そして、わためぇとジャージ！
Next is the Watamate Jersey!
わための制服衣装とお揃い、色違いの黄色いジャージになってまして、
It's a yellow jersey that matches my school uniform outfit.
背面にはわためが描き下ろした
On the back, there's a print
わためぇとエアギターがプリントされております！
of Watamate playing air guitar, drawn by me!
さらに、ぬいぐるみキーホルダー制服ジャージ衣装ver.！
Next is the Plushie Keychain (School Uniform Jersey ver.)!
これがもうめちゃくちゃ可愛い！
This one is just super cute!
お出かけにも連れて行きやすいサイズのぬいぐるみです。
It's a plushie that's easy to take with you on outings.
ぜひ、色んな所へ連れて行って、ハバナイス（？）してください！
Please take it with you and show it around everywhere!
そしてラスト！MACCO先生描き下ろしの缶バッジ4種セット！
Finally! A set of 4 button badges by MACCO-sensei!
どのわためも可愛いので、ぜひ推しバッグなどに使ってください！
Every Watame is cute, so please use them on your fan bags!
こちらのフルセットをご購入していただいた方には、
Those who purchase the full set will receive
角巻わためのショートボイスセットとチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきます！
a short voice set and a cheki-style bromide card!
ボイスはなんと15種類！
There are a whopping 15 types of voices!
チェキ風ブロマイドカードには、直筆サイン＆メッセージを、
And for the cheki-style bromide card,
購入した方全員に書かせていただきます！
I will personally sign and write a message for everyone!
さらに、タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、
Additionally, as a full-set bonus,
去年から発売されたホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで
you'll get a card for the Hololive Official Card Game,
使用できるカードが1枚ついてきます！
which was released last year!
このカードは、ホロライブプロダクション
This card is only for those who purchase
オフィシャルショップで購入された方のみ対象となります。
from the Hololive Production Official Shop.
特典に付くのは、推しをアピールできるキーカード
The bonus card is an 'Oshi Holomen Card,'
「推しホロメンカード」です。
a key card to show off your favorite member.
カードの詳細や遊び方については、
For card details and how to play,
ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームの公式ホームページにてご確認ください！
please check the official Hololive Card Game website!
とっても盛りだくさんな最強グッズなので、
It's a truly packed set of the best merch,
ぜひたくさん買っていただけると嬉しいです！
so I'd be happy if you'd buy lots of them!
そして、この後10時15分からは、
And starting at 10:15 PM today,
メン限3Dライブがありますので、
there's a members-only 3D live!
ビリのMVを見て、グッズをチェックして、
Watch the 'Biri' MV, check out the merch,
メン限ライブもぜひ見に来てください！
and please come watch the member-only live too!
メン限ライブでは、温度差で風邪を引く可能性が…！？
In the live, you might catch a cold from the temperature difference...?!
みんなのこと待ってるねー！
I'll be waiting for you all!
ホロライブを応援してくれるみんな
わためいと / watamates
Everyone who supports Hololive
Watamates
メンバーシップ限定 アンコールライブ！！
Start 22:15〜
Membership-only Encore Live!!
Starting at 22:15